Home Address: 523 Charlestown Meadows Dr Westborough, MA 01581 Campus Address: 22 Coyne Court, Apt #104 Madison, WI 53715

Email: arshadmhabib@gmail.com
Phone: (608) 218-0542

CAREER OBJECTIVE

University IT senior with 3+ years of work experience aiming to leverage proven knowledge of advanced technology, web, and application development skills to successfully fill a Security Analyst, Software Engineering (Security) or QA Test Engineering intern or full-time role. Seeking to continue my education in pursuit of a Professional Master's Degree in Information Security.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF WISCONSIN-MADISON- Madison, WI (2017 - Present)

Major: B.S. Computer Science (Security) (Expected grad May 2021) Certificate (minor): Business & Entrepreneurship

- Clubs and Organizations: MSA Logistics and Marketing Chair, AI Club, Honors College, HHRD, MCC and WIC Volunteer RELEVANT COURSEWORK (In Progress)
- **Software Security:** Developed applied understanding of secure coding (e.g exceptions), threat and attack modeling (e.g injection, serialization, web, mobile attacks), Penetration Testing, FPVA, static code analysis tools and Fuzz Testing.
- **Cryptography:** Understood classical cipher encryption and decryption, cryptanalysis, block ciphers, modern public key techniques (e.g. RSA algorithm) and cryptographic protocols to securely transmit data.
- **Software Engineering:** Hands-on application of Software Development Life Cycle and Waterfall methodologies in project team with experience in Back-end development in Flask with REST API's, debugging and unit testing.

SKILLS

- Tech Stacks: Object-Oriented: Java, Python (Flask & Django frameworks), HTML, CSS, C, Javascript, R, SQL
- Tools: Unix / Linux, Intellij, Eclipse, Cloud JIRA, Antivirus, Network Firewall, VPN, Kibana, Confluence Wiki
- Understanding of endpoint protection, email, network, encryption, and authentication protocols.
- Attentive to detail with effective time-management, teamwork and systematic thinking to find efficient solutions.
- Enthusiastic about personal growth and improving security skills.
- Accumulated debugging experience with TDD and White Box testing using JUnit, query and traditional testing methods.
- **Developed** knowledge in troubleshooting problems on Windows 7, 8 and 10, Android, and iOS.
- Softwares: MS Office (Excel, Publisher, Visual Studio, Project), Sharepoint, G Suite, Trello, Adobe XD
- Certifications: CompTIA Security+ (Pursuing)

WORK EXPERIENCE

INTERNSHIP @ TDS TELECOMMUNICATIONS LLC, Madison, WI, USA

Software Engineer Intern (Security), June 2020 - Present

- Monitors and remediates customer-initiated incident tickets including email management for phishing, spam, and
 accessibility issues, login issues, network IP blacklist, 404 errors for blocked websites and log management to provide swift
 resolutions to enhance customer communication and satisfaction for TDS products and services. Additionally, creates
 documentation on Confluence to add value for the team.
- Assists in Adobe Experience Manager development in Django for new feature additions to the website and resolutions of bugs in JSP, XML, and Python file types in an organized Kanban workflow using Agile methodology to increase efficiency and accountability.
- Tests code using query commands and unit testing to identify software issues and provides efficient solutions to increase customer attractiveness towards the brand

ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION MANAGEMENT SERVICES @ UW-MADISON, Madison, WI, USA Computer Systems Technician. Mar 2018 - August 2019

- Accelerated the deployment service of hardware and software to customers in compliance with the AIMS routine of package installation, customization, configuration and advocated effective and satisfactory solutions to enhance company reputation.
- Allocated users into domains and groups in the Microsoft active directory to manage and secure network resources.
- Outlined the core tasks at team meetings which improved task completion and efficiency by 20%.

IT SUMMER INTERNSHIP @ WORCESTER ISLAMIC CENTER— Worcester, MA, USA

IT Management Intern, May 2019 - Aug 2019, Management & Graphic Design Intern, July 2018 - August 2018

- Administered and thoroughly analyzed the Mohid financial database software to enhance customer experience.
- Designed the Standard Operating Procedures for community events, facility use policies and committees.

- Chaired the WIC Magazine project accumulating useful annual updates of the center which enhanced communication and community satisfaction by more than 50% and specialized in graphic design, editorial, and content creation.
- Restructured the hierarchy of the Institution's designated sectors which improved service quality and productivity by 50%.